# Pranav Ahuja

I am a self-motivated, positive attitude person with a curiosity to learn things. My inspiration came from a world that has been integrated together and everything I do, learn and experience is the step towards inculcating the same. Being an Electronics enthusiast, I have worked in the field of IOT (Internet of Things) and Embedded Systems. I have experience working on STM32, AVR, Node MCU, ESP32, Arduino. I have experience in programming languages like C, Embedded C, C++, Python, Java, HTML, CSS.

#### CONTACT

+91 9650691311

pranav.ahuja3@gmail.com

https://pranav-ahuja.github.io/pranavahuja/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/pranav-ahuja-17094a14a/

#### **PROJECTS**

# **Unmanned Aerial Vehicle**

January, 2022 - Present

- Build an UAV using Arduino Flight Controller.
- Components includes, Accelerometer sensor, ESC, Brushless Motors, nRF24L01 communication modules, Joystick, Arduino Uno, Arduino Nano.

## Bicycle Theft Alarm

October, 2021 - November, 2021

- · Build an alarm system triggered bicycle anti theft device.
- · Works using GSM module.
- Sense the motion of the bicycle using motion sensor.
- It will place a call to your mobile device.

## **Posture Monitoring Device**

June, 2019 - January, 2020

- Build a posture monitoring device, based on ESP32 micro controller.
- Correct the posture by producing vibration signals, if wrong posture is detected.
- Send the data to mobile phone using Bluetooth.

## **EXPERIENCE**

## System Engineer

Infosys · November 2020 - Present

- SAP ATTP
  - o Regulatory reporting for Indonesia, Europe, China.
  - o Master data creation and processing.
  - o Serialization and serial number management.
- Trainings
  - o JAVA
  - Data Structure
  - SQL
  - o SAP MM
  - SAP ATTP

# Intern

Defense Research and Organization · June 2019 - July 2019

- Research in Missile Guidance Systems
  - o Classification of Missiles and their working.
  - o Classification of Missile Guidance Systems.
  - Aerodynamics



#### **SKILLS**

Embedded C C++ Python HTML CSS Node MCU IOT Circuit Design PCB Design OOP Thingworx STM32 Arduino AVR ESP32 HTTPS XMPP Bluetooth **MQTT** WiFi **Data Structure** 

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor of Technology**

Bharati Vidyapeeth College of Engineering, Pune

Major: Electronics and Telecommunication

2016 - 2020 | 9.32 CGPA

## **COURSES**

Hands-on Internet of Things University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign

Microcontroller Embedded C Programming Udemy

#### CERTIFICATIONS

Infosys IOT Professional Certificate Infosys . April-2022